<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 09:19:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>4 Golden Rules for Optimizing Your Payment Page and Boosting Conversion</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-golden-rules-optimizing-payment-page-boosting-conversion/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-golden-rules-optimizing-payment-page-boosting-conversion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 07:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camille Sila]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19414</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Most customers who go into a brick and mortar spend some money before they leave. But typically only a small percentage of Internet users make a purchase. How can you improve your conversion rate? That&#8217;s the question that every merchant asks themselves. Site design, videos, and multiple product photos with different angles all have a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-golden-rules-optimizing-payment-page-boosting-conversion/">4 Golden Rules for Optimizing Your Payment Page and Boosting Conversion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Most customers who go into a brick and mortar spend some money before they leave. But typically only a small percentage of Internet users make a purchase. How can you improve your conversion rate? That&#8217;s the question that every merchant asks themselves.<br />
Site design, videos, and multiple product photos with different angles all have a strong influence on a customer&#8217;s decision to make a purchase from a website. But the payment page is another strategic point for optimizing your conversions.</p>
<p>David Chaouat, Partner Manager at Ingenico Payment Services, is an expert in online payment services. Here he reveals 4 golden rules to quickly optimize your payment page and boost your conversion rate.<br />
<span id="more-19414"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #73bd43;">1. Elements of credibility</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s fundamental to provide an atmosphere of trust throughout the purchasing experience. If customers don&#8217;t trust your e-commerce site, they won&#8217;t finalize their purchases with you!<br />
Think hard about the customer experience that you would like to offer at checkout. If your brand is not very well-known, or isn&#8217;t yet a recognized name in the marketplace, you should consider a visible redirect to a trusted third party page (PSP or bank). That way you can rely on a known partner, and benefit from their trustworthiness (SSL Certificates, transaction references, banking partner logos, etc.)<br />
If your brand is already well-known and trustworthy, then you can choose an integrated order gateway where the redirect to the trusted third party is invisible. In that case, don&#8217;t forget the essential elements for the payment page: SSL certificate, the amount of the transaction, the transaction reference number and a trusted logo that&#8217;s well-known on the marketplace (such as a bank, PSP, Verisign, etc.)</p>
<h2 style="color: #73bd43;">2. Offer payment methods adapted to your customers</h2>
<p>When you let your customers choose how to pay, they&#8217;ll be more inclined to complete their purchase. For example: a Dutch customer might prefer to pay with iDEAL while a French customer might prefer to use a credit card. So make sure that your payment partner offers you the necessary payment methods, and that they are easy and clear to use.<br />
Then, adapt your payment page, dynamically displaying payment methods according to your customers&#8217; location or nationality. Don&#8217;t display every payment method each time. Segment your customers to include only the relevant payment methods.</p>
<h2 style="color: #73bd43;">3. Customize the page design with your store&#8217;s look</h2>
<p>So that there&#8217;s not a visual break between your site and the service provider&#8217;s payment page, you should do something to customize it. The important thing is for the page to be clear and fluid: just putting your logo in, and using your site&#8217;s fonts and colours is typically enough to make it seem smooth. If you can, think about putting a phone number on this page so you can recover the sale if there&#8217;s a problem.<br />
For those customers who might be unsettled by the redirect, you can also add a home button and links giving different ways to return to your site. Customers these days are better informed, and have come to expect external payment pages on sites. They&#8217;re no longer as unsettled by a redirect.</p>
<h2 style="color: #73bd43;">4. A payment page that adapts to every format</h2>
<p>Your site is no doubt already set up for different formats (PC, tablet, smartphone). It would be a pity to ruin all of your efforts by only offering one payment page format. The payment page must also be fluid and practical for customers browsing on their smartphone. It’s easier for customers to finalize a purchase if they don&#8217;t have to zoom and scroll to enter their card number.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-18265" alt="ingenico" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/ingenico.jpg" width="480" height="197" /></p>
<p>Ingenico Payment is the ideal partner to help you put the advice from this article into practice and boost your sales. When you download the Ingenico Payment payment module, you&#8217;re also protecting your company from fraud and ensuring your online business will run smoothly and successfully!</p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/1798-ogone.html" target="_blank">Download Ingenico Payment for free</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-golden-rules-optimizing-payment-page-boosting-conversion/">4 Golden Rules for Optimizing Your Payment Page and Boosting Conversion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-golden-rules-optimizing-payment-page-boosting-conversion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Counter-Intuition: Why a Tighter Selection Means More Sales</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/counter-intuition-tighter-selection-means-sales/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/counter-intuition-tighter-selection-means-sales/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shabbir Nooruddin (Guest Contributor)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19392</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When you sell online, it&#8217;s tempting to want to carry as much as you can in your store &#8211; after all, more products equals more sales &#8211; right? The more products you have, the greater the likelihood that someone browsing your store will find something they want or like, and buy it &#8211; right? Sure [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/counter-intuition-tighter-selection-means-sales/">Counter-Intuition: Why a Tighter Selection Means More Sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you sell online, it&#8217;s tempting to want to carry as much as you can in your store &#8211; after all, more products equals more sales &#8211; right?</p>
<p>The more products you have, the greater the likelihood that someone browsing your store will find something they want or like, and buy it &#8211; right?</p>
<p>Sure &#8211; if your store happens to be Amazon or Walmart. But if you&#8217;re a small business owner like the rest of us, then good luck trying to sell that kind of catalog.</p>
<p><span id="more-19392"></span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #2f5288">What Amazon and Walmart do</span></h4>
<p>Amazon and Walmart have been around for years. In that time, they&#8217;ve perfected the art of being “everything” stores &#8211; it&#8217;s the very concept their brands are founded on.</p>
<p>To be “everything” stores, they have to buy in bulk, spend millions of dollars securing inexpensive inventory, sell everything at super-tight margins and expect to make up any losses through volume.</p>
<p>They also spend millions and millions of dollars on advertising to reach customers &#8211; in fact, Amazon is one of the <a title="Google Adwords" href="http://www.wordstream.com/articles/google-earnings" target="_blank">largest consumers of Google Adwords</a>.</p>
<p>You may have noticed that I used the word “millions” a few times in the above paragraphs. Unless you have millions to spend on advertising &#8211; I know I sure don&#8217;t &#8211; it&#8217;s highly unlikely that you can sell everything and be successful at it.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #2f5288">What the rest of us (shouldn&#8217;t) do</span></h4>
<p>While most people new to ecommerce don&#8217;t make the cardinal sin of listing everything on their store, they still try to carry too much.</p>
<p>The problem with listing too much is that you stretch yourself too thin &#8211; think “jack-of-all-trades, master of none.”</p>
<p>So what do I mean by “too much”? Well, lets say you wanted to open a store in the coffee niche. A new store selling “too much” in the coffee niche would try to offer every coffee machine ever made, as well as filters and hundreds of different coffees.</p>
<p>The reason Amazon can get away with being a jack-of-all-trades is that they&#8217;ve spent the better part of 20 years nurturing trust in that brand image. A new store that tries to sell a similar variety of products doesn&#8217;t command the same respect and will struggle to win over customers.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #2f5288">Less is more</span></h4>
<p>In ecommerce, less is sometimes more for small businesses. If you&#8217;re selling something that can be found on Amazon, you have to be very good to be profitable. To position yourself against the bigger players, it sometimes helps to have a tighter product selection.</p>
<p>A tighter product selection suggests expertise. Nobody goes to Amazon and thinks, “Man, these guys are experts about what they sell. I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;ll be able to answer any questions I have.”<br />
In fact, because there&#8217;s so little product-specific information available on Amazon, an entire industry of websites specializing in product reviews exists &#8211; to direct people right to Amazon!</p>
<p>Now, if you head to a boutique ecommerce store specializing in one product line, you know those guys are experts &#8211; they&#8217;ll listen to your concerns and help you choose the right product for your needs. They serve the dual role of product review website and online store.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #2f5288">Niche down</span></h4>
<p>What does it mean to “niche down”? Very simply, it means to remove products and tighten your offer to respond to a more specific customer need. To understand what products to cut, you must first understand your customer.</p>
<p><a title="Andrew Youderian" href="http://www.ecommercefuel.com/inside-relaunch-online-store/" target="_blank">Andrew Youderian figured out</a>, for example, that most of his former trolling motor shop customers were actually looking for bow mount trolling motors, so he niched down from trolling motors to the more specific bow mount trolling motors.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve already got a store up and running, go through your orders and try to identify some trends &#8211; chances are some of your products are selling much, much better than others &#8211; that&#8217;s where your opportunity lies. Identify the need and focus your marketing efforts on those areas where you are already seen as an expert.</p>
<p>If you haven&#8217;t got a store yet, go through subreddits and forums related to your future market to find common denominators or trends. You can start building your store around a need. Another approach is to cast a wider net when you first start out, with the intent to specialize as trends begin to appear.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #2f5288">Key takeaways</span></h4>
<p>When it comes to small business ecommerce, less is more. Once you have your audience and customer base down, then you can think about expanding your selection with carefully curated products that you know your audience will love and want to buy.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/counter-intuition-tighter-selection-means-sales/">Counter-Intuition: Why a Tighter Selection Means More Sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/counter-intuition-tighter-selection-means-sales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Remedies for the Post-Holiday Ecommerce Sales Slump</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-remedies-post-holiday-ecommerce-sales-slump/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-remedies-post-holiday-ecommerce-sales-slump/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 09:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19408</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Christmas may be over and gone, but opportunities for making online sales aren’t. In fact, the post-holiday season is more interesting than ever for ecommerce stores, thanks to the rise in popularity of gift cards and online shopping in general. Many shoppers eschew holiday sales entirely for certain items, instead waiting to pounce after the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-remedies-post-holiday-ecommerce-sales-slump/">3 Remedies for the Post-Holiday Ecommerce Sales Slump</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Christmas may be over and gone, but opportunities for making online sales aren’t. In fact, the post-holiday season is more interesting than ever for ecommerce stores, thanks to the rise in popularity of gift cards and online shopping in general.</p>
<p>Many shoppers eschew holiday sales entirely for certain items, instead waiting to pounce after the New Year when they know the same products will go for a fraction of the price. While deep post-holiday discounts are the most common strategy for clearing out inventory, when done haphazardly they can seem like desperate cries for help.<br />
<span id="more-19408"></span></p>
<p>Here are a few alternative ideas to ensure healthy business after the holiday rush, and cultivate good relationships with new and existing customers.</p>
<h2 style="color: #5e8f71">Returns and exchanges</h2>
<p>Your customers are burnt out from the holidays and dreading the entire return-and-exchange process. If you can make the experience easy, or better yet, pleasant for them, you can turn this dreary aspect of the holidays into an opportunity to build customer loyalty.</p>
<p><strong>Unsatisfied customers are people too</strong><br />
You worked hard to deck out your online shop for the holidays and make sure your customers had a stellar experience. Don&#8217;t stop now; returns and exchanges may not be fun, but they provide a great opportunity to impress your customers with attentive, personalized service.</p>
<p><strong>Lend a listening ear with instant chat</strong><br />
The best way to ease the returns and exchange process is to have a simple policy clearly stated on your shop site. Back this up with enhanced <span style="text-decoration: underline">live chat</span> capabilities—this is your chance to show off your customer service skills with friendly, real-time help. As an added bonus, personalize your live chat windows with photos of real people, not stock shots.</p>
<p><strong>Reduce returns with an incentive they can&#8217;t refuse</strong><br />
Looked at in another light, a return can be a great opportunity to convert a long-term customer. Why not offer free shipping or a modest discount if the customer decides to make an exchange instead of asking for a refund? They get a pleasant surprise and you get renewed business.</p>
<h2 style="color: #5e8f71">Deals and discounts that make a difference</h2>
<p>We wouldn&#8217;t usually tell you to compete on price, but the holiday and post-holiday period is a unique time when customers expect discounts. That doesn&#8217;t mean you have to do what everyone else is doing; find a unique way to stand out as customers get ready to spend their Christmas loot and cash in on gift cards. Try one of these:</p>
<p><strong>Give back a bit of what you get</strong><br />
An interesting way to differentiate yourself is to give a portion of proceeds to a charity you support. After months in the consumerist tornado that is the holiday season, many people are happy to see some of their money support a good cause.</p>
<p><strong>Buy one, get this free</strong><br />
If you’ve got excess inventory to move, consider offering a free product with the purchase of a full-price item. This works very well with perishable or time-sensitive products, like seasonal fashion items: throw in a printed scarf for every pair of full-price jeans purchased. Even if you only break even on those items, you’ve saved yourself invenotry costs and shelf space by moving products that would have otherwise gone to waste.</p>
<p><strong>Bundle up</strong><br />
If you have complimentary products that you need to get rid of, consider bundling them and targeting customers who bought a related item. Accessories and refills are great candidates for this move: picks and strings for a new guitar; chargers, adapters and cases for phones. Mix and match to see what works for your business.</p>
<p><strong>A good old-fashioned contest</strong><br />
Drum up interest with a contest: ask customers to submit their favorite holiday photos or best image of your product in use. Everyone who participates wins, even if it’s just 5% off their next purchase. Use the contest to promote a new or best-selling product and award one to the winner.</p>
<p><strong>Say thank you</strong><br />
Your store’s success leans heavily on customer loyalty, so why not thank your customers for making your year a great one? Offer them a small discount that they can pass on to friends and family. It’ll give them a reason to visit your store in January and maybe even attract a few new visitors.</p>
<p><strong>The undiscount: a new product for the new year</strong><br />
A new product launch is a great way to get customers’ attention without slashing prices. You’ll need to be organized to pull it off, but if you do it right, you can take advantage of new year momentum to make a big impact.</p>
<h2 style="color: #5e8f71">Lessons and resolutions</h2>
<p>The post-holiday season is also a good time to take stock of the past year in order to prepare for the one coming up. While you’ll certainly be discounting some items and working to clear inventory for new products, it’s important to take the time to do important marketing work that will put you on track for the NEXT holiday season.</p>
<p><strong>Mind your data</strong><br />
The holiday season should have given you a wealth of data about your customers. You can use it to segment your contact list and push personalized offers on products you want to move to the customers you’re sure will be interested. For example, if you know who bought a phone this year, send an email offering an accessory bundle. Or if you’re an apparel store with excess items in a few select sizes, send targeted offers to customers you know have bought those sizes previously. You avoid swamping customers with offers that won’t interest them.</p>
<p><strong>Pay attention to purchasing patterns</strong><br />
You’ll have learned a lot about your customers this holiday season, but also quite a bit about your products. What is selling full price? What goes on sale? Use this data to tailor your marketing and evaluate which products you should be marking down to move and which are going to carry you through the year.</p>
<ul style="margin-left: 30px">
<li><strong style="color: #5e8f71">Well-performing products:</strong> The holidays probably gave you a good idea of what products people are willing to pay full price for. These are good items to build bundles and promotions around now and to focus marketing efforts on throughout the year.</li>
<li><strong style="color: #5e8f71">Products with promise:</strong> Do some products attract a lot of attention but few conversions? Try promoting them with a light post-holiday sale or simply put them in the spotlight when you communicate with customers.</li>
<li><strong style="color: #5e8f71">Troubled products:</strong> if certain products only sell well at a discount it might be time to clear them out. Post-holiday sales are a great opportunity to make a special “Clearance” category. These are products that might also bundle well.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Don’t neglect abandoned carts</strong><br />
Many customers use carts in lieu of a wish list. They often expect to receive a reminder about their cart, so don’t miss this opportunity to follow up and recoup unfinished sales.</p>
<p><strong>Show off your social skills </strong><br />
The holidays may be over, but don’t shelve your marketing efforts just yet. Use social media to keep the conversation going. If you decide to incorporate a charity donation, social media is a great way to engage your customers and raise awareness. The same goes for if you hold a post-holiday contest.</p>
<p><strong>Take down the holiday decorations (and deals!)</strong><br />
This is one that’s easy to do, but also easy to overlook. Unfortunately, the consequences of forgetting could be unpleasant for your reputation and your bottom line. If you promised free shipping during the holidays, be sure to remove it from your promotional tools if you don’t plan on continuing in the new year. Did you make a low-price guarantee during the holidays that your post-holiday sale is going to conflict with? Do this now so you can move on to more important things.</p>
<h2 style="color: #5e8f71">Key takeaways</h2>
<ul style="margin-left: 30px">
<li>Personalize the returns and exchange process</li>
<li>Use incentives to convert returns into exchanges or even purchases</li>
<li>Avoid relying solely on deep discounts; make creative offers</li>
<li>Thank your customers</li>
<li>Use data to segment customers and target marketing efforts</li>
<li>Analyze product performance and market accordingly</li>
<li>Follow up on abandoned cards</li>
<li>Be social in the new year</li>
<li>Review holiday promises and take down decorations</li>
</ul>
<p>The holidays are over, but the new year is just beginning. What are you doing to make sure it’s a successful one? Have you tried any of these suggestions? Let us know what’s working for you!</p>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="20%" />
<p>Ready to make 2015 your best year yet? Get started with our updated 2015 <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-calendar">ecommerce calendar</a>. From expert advice to key sales dates, it has everything you need to prepare your year.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-remedies-post-holiday-ecommerce-sales-slump/">3 Remedies for the Post-Holiday Ecommerce Sales Slump</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-remedies-post-holiday-ecommerce-sales-slump/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Ecommerce Design Trends for 2015</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-ecommerce-design-trends-2015/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-ecommerce-design-trends-2015/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 10:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juan Manuel Molina]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19356</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Is 2015 the year you finally get around to updating your website design? Then you’re in luck! PrestaShop has handpicked a few examples of the latest ecommerce web design trends to help you develop an updated design adapted to your business. Use this list as a guide for template and module research, or as a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-ecommerce-design-trends-2015/">5 Ecommerce Design Trends for 2015</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is 2015 the year you finally get around to updating your website design? Then you’re in luck! PrestaShop has handpicked a few examples of the latest ecommerce web design trends to help you develop an updated design adapted to your business. Use this list as a guide for template and module research, or as a reference when discussing changes with your designer.<br />
<span id="more-19356"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #45394d">1. Full-screen images</h2>
<p>If you’ve worked hard developing beautiful product photography, then you’ll be ready to ride the full-screen image trend. While the home slider is where large images tend to shine, that’s not the only place you can use them effectively. Check out how <span style="font-style: italic">New World Order NYC</span> is using them as background for their product pages.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.suncoo-paris.com/en/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19361" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="Suncoo Paris" alt="Suncoo Paris" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/big-image-suncoo-paris.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.basus.fr/en/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19357" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="Basus" alt="Basus" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/big-images-basus.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.menzclub.com.au/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19358" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="Menzclub" alt="Menzclub" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/big-images-menzclub.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.tb-groupe.fr/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19359" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="TB Groupe" alt="TB Groupe" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/big-images-tb-groupe.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://thenewworldordernyc.com/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19360" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="The New World Order NYC" alt="The New World Order NYC" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/big-images-thenewworldordernyc.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.april77.fr/en/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19362" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="April77" alt="April77" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/big-screen-april77.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;margin-bottom: 70px"><a href="http://www.bimbaylola.com/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19363" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="Bimba y lola" alt="Bimba y lola" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/big-screen-bimba-y-lola.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<h2 style="color: #45394d">2. Flat and Material Design, Bright Colors</h2>
<p>2014 was the year of <a href="http://www.awwwards.com/websites/flat-design/" target="_blank">Flat Design</a>, characterized by flat colors, minimalist design and simple typography, all used to eliminate any impression of three dimensions. This year we’ll be seeing more of <a href="http://www.google.com/design/spec/material-design/introduction.html" target="_blank">Material Design</a>, a design language developed by Google that draws its inspiration from the textural world of paper and ink. Both design trends rely on strong graphic design, so be brave and use bright colors in your site, especially if your brand is young and has a sense of humor.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.m-moustache.com/en/robert/169-leon-cuir-noir.html" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19371" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="M Moustache" alt="M Moustache" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/colors-m-moustache2.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.m-moustache.com/en/robert/169-leon-cuir-noir.html" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19370" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="M Moustache" alt="M Moustache" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/colors-m-moustache.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.loobow.fr/103-wc-couleur-jaune-gamme-yellow-cab" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19369" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="Loobow" alt="Loobow" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/colors-loobow.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.bioseptyl.fr/brosses-a-dents-adultes/8-blanche-nurse.html" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19368" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="Bioseptyl" alt="Bioseptyl" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/colors-bioseptyl.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;margin-bottom: 70px"><a href="http://www.pa-design.com/en/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19372" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="pa Design" alt="pa Design" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/colors-pa-design.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<h2 style="color: #45394d">3. Flashcards</h2>
<p>Give visitors everything they need to know about your product at a glance: develop a “flashcard” for each product that contains product name and description, social sharing buttons, price and of course, a “Buy Now” call-to-action button.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.theverge.com/a/holiday-gift-ideas-2014/25-100" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19365" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="The Verge Holiday Gift Ideas" alt="The Verge Holiday Gift Ideas" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/cards-the-verge-holiday-gift-ideas.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://wallcaps.fr/fr/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19366" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="Wallcaps" alt="Wallcaps" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/cards-wallcaps.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.wannabk.com/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19367" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="Wannabek" alt="Wannabek" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/cards-wannabek.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;margin-bottom: 70px"><a href="http://housen.ro/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19364" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="Housen" alt="Housen" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/cards-housen-ro.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<h2 style="color: #45394d">4. Parallax</h2>
<p>You’ve probably been stopped by more than one website with tantalizing background animation. That’s the parallax effect. While it can be very impressive when used correctly, it’s also easy to go overboard and lose sight of your main goal: presenting your products. Remember, animation and effects should support sales, not overshadow website design. Here, Manoush animates page navigation while their colorful patterns liven up the background without distracting from the products themselves.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;margin-bottom: 70px"><a href="http://www.manoush.com/e-shop/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19375" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="Manoush" alt="Manoush" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/parallax-manoush.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<h2 style="color: #45394d">5. Minimalist Buttons</h2>
<p>Buttons with a minimalist design subtly suggest a call to action, without taking away from beautiful background images. They’re particularly useful if you need to include a call to action in your main slider.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.zeina-alliances.com/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19374" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" title="Zeina" alt="Zeina" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/minimal-buttons-zeina.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.oelwein.fr/fr/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19373" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5" alt="Oelwein" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/minimal-buttons-oelwein.png" width="657" height="400" /></a></p>
<h4 style="color: #73bd43">Key takeaways</h4>
<p><strong style="color: #73bd43">1.</strong> Showcase great photography through full-screen images</p>
<p><strong style="color: #73bd43">2.</strong> Flat and material design will remain strong web design trends in 2015</p>
<p><strong style="color: #73bd43">3.</strong> Product flashcards give customers everything they need at a glance</p>
<p><strong style="color: #73bd43">4.</strong> Be prudent with parallax</p>
<p><strong style="color: #73bd43">5.</strong> Simplify call-to-action buttons to keep attention focused on images</p>
<p>These are just a few of the ecommerce design trends that we can look forward to in 2015. What design trends are you looking forward to following? Discover what’s best for your business and renew your online shop by using one of <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/3-templates-prestashop" target="_blank">our themes</a> or get in touch with one of our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners" target="_blank">associated web agencies</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-ecommerce-design-trends-2015/">5 Ecommerce Design Trends for 2015</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-ecommerce-design-trends-2015/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecommerce Calendar: 52 Secrets for a Successful 2015</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-calendar-52-secrets-for-a-successful-2015/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-calendar-52-secrets-for-a-successful-2015/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 14:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cécile Dubouis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19243</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Forget about New Year&#8217;s resolutions, we’ve got you covered! Put an end to all those good New Year’s Day intentions that evaporate mid-month (really, has any resolution made it past January 15th?). This year, we&#8217;re going to help you make real progress all 52 weeks of the year. Being an online retailer means doing 12 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-calendar-52-secrets-for-a-successful-2015/">Ecommerce Calendar: 52 Secrets for a Successful 2015</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Forget about New Year&#8217;s resolutions, we’ve got you covered!</p>
<p>Put an end to all those good New Year’s Day intentions that evaporate mid-month (really, has any resolution made it past January 15<sup>th</sup>?).</p>
<p>This year, we&#8217;re going to help you make real progress all 52 weeks of the year.</p>
<p><span id="more-19243"></span></p>
<p>Being an online retailer means doing 12 jobs at once – developer, accountant, logistics coordinator, designer, editor, salesperson – which makes it difficult to plan ahead and prioritize.</p>
<p>To help make your store a success this year, we&#8217;re delighted to present the <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-calendar" target="_blank">2015 Ecommerce Calendar</a><b>, broken down week by week and adapted to country-specific markets and events</b>.</p>
<h2 style="color: #4d7e3d">12 pages of tools and advice</h2>
<p><b>Each week</b>, <b>you’ll find a tip</b> for boosting traffic or conversion rates, or an idea for enhancing user experience, increasing average cart value, gaining customer loyalty, and more.</p>
<p>To make life easier, we also suggest a <b>selection of tools</b>—to help you create promotions and improve communication, for example—that will save you time when managing your store.</p>
<p>Is a <b>major sales event</b> coming up – the Back to School season, Christmas, Mother&#8217;s Day, Black Friday? No problem! You&#8217;ll have everything you need to plan ahead and understand <b>how and when to start getting your store ready</b>.</p>
<p>Each month, a PrestaShop merchant will share <b>advice</b> that has contributed to his or her success.</p>
<p>And if you&#8217;re not used to taking it easy, we&#8217;ll even tell you when it&#8217;s time to relax!</p>
<h2 style="color: #4d7e3d">Customize your calendar</h2>
<p>The tips are suggestions from experts on how to enhance your website, help you get organized, and show you your online store in a whole new light.</p>
<p>The calendar also contains sections that need to be filled in &#8211; by you.</p>
<p><b>Your store is unique</b>. You know your customers, products and website culture better than anyone else. Write in all the events that you would like to organize throughout the year, now.</p>
<h2 style="color: #4d7e3d">Key figures</h2>
<h4>THE 2015 E-COMMERCE CALENDAR:</h4>
<ul style="margin: 0 0 0 15px">
<li>0 cents to download</li>
<li>1 circular calendar showing peak periods in the year at a glance</li>
<li>8 countries included (France, Spain, the US, Italy, Germany, the Netherlands, the UK and Poland)</li>
<li>12 customized pages with advice from real merchants</li>
<li>52+ ecommerce tips</li>
<li>327 recent online store audits, which inspired us to make this calendar for you!</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Next year we hope to offer calendars for even more countries.</p>
<p>Do you want to help?</p>
<p>Let us know about any major events in your region, or tips you&#8217;d like to share with other merchants in your country, using the email address <a href="mailto:calendar@prestashop.com">calendar@prestashop.com</a>.</p>
<p>Wishing you a fantastic 2015 and a successful ecommerce year!</p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5">A thank you to </span><a style="line-height: 1.5" title="Pagination.com" href="http://www.pagination.com" target="_blank">Pagination.com</a><span style="line-height: 1.5"> for its help integrating the template and data.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;font-size: 18px"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-calendar" target="_blank">Download calendar now</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-calendar-52-secrets-for-a-successful-2015/">Ecommerce Calendar: 52 Secrets for a Successful 2015</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-calendar-52-secrets-for-a-successful-2015/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Credit Cards vs. Fraudsters: The Evolution of Credit Card Security [Infographic]</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/credit-cards-vs-fraudsters-the-evolution-of-credit-card-security/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/credit-cards-vs-fraudsters-the-evolution-of-credit-card-security/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 13:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19259</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that in 2009, over half a million credit cards were compromised? What about in 2010, Canada alone experienced $366 million in fraud? As online merchants, it’s important to know how credit card security features have evolved to prevent unauthorized credit card use. It’s why today we present this infographic: Credit Cards vs. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/credit-cards-vs-fraudsters-the-evolution-of-credit-card-security/">Credit Cards vs. Fraudsters: The Evolution of Credit Card Security [Infographic]</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that in 2009, over half a million credit cards were compromised? What about in 2010, Canada alone experienced $366 million in fraud?</p>
<p>As online merchants, it’s important to know how credit card security features have evolved to prevent unauthorized credit card use. It’s why today we present this infographic: Credit Cards vs. Fraudsters: The Evolution of Credit Card Security.</p>
<p><span id="more-19259"></span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19272" title="desjardin" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/desjardin.jpg" alt="" width="573" height="4760" /></p>
<p>This infographic is sponsored by Desjardins, our preferred Canadian payment processor. Start accepting payments on your Canadian online shop by downloading<a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/14656-desjardins.html" target="_blank"> the free Desjardins’ module</a>.</p>
<p>Seamlessly implement this payment solution to start processing <strong>credit card payments, refunds, and more!</strong> To help you limit credit card risk, all Desjardins accounts include a full range of fraud prevention tools including:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li>CVV2 Validation</li>
<li>3-D Secure Validation</li>
<li>Fraud Prevention Module with
<ol>
<ul>
<li>Order Filter by IP Address</li>
<li>Order Filter by Credit Card Number</li>
</ul>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/credit-cards-vs-fraudsters-the-evolution-of-credit-card-security/">Credit Cards vs. Fraudsters: The Evolution of Credit Card Security [Infographic]</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/credit-cards-vs-fraudsters-the-evolution-of-credit-card-security/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Now available – Discover and download PrestaShop v1.6.0.11!</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/now-available-discover-and-download-prestashop-v1-6-0-11/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/now-available-discover-and-download-prestashop-v1-6-0-11/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 14:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quentin Audrain]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19286</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop 1.6.0.11 is here We are launching straight into 2015 by wishing you a very happy New Year and by making PrestaShop 1.6.0.11 available for download. We would like to thank the whole Community, who has helped us test, debug and improve this latest version. It&#8217;s thanks to you too that it&#8217;s all been possible! [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/now-available-discover-and-download-prestashop-v1-6-0-11/">Now available – Discover and download PrestaShop v1.6.0.11!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4><span style="color: #2f5288;">PrestaShop 1.6.0.11 is here</span></h4>
<p>We are launching straight into 2015 by wishing you a very happy New Year and by making PrestaShop 1.6.0.11 available for download.<br />
We would like to thank the whole Community, who has helped us test, debug and improve this latest version. It&#8217;s thanks to you too that it&#8217;s all been possible!<br />
<span id="more-19286"></span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #2f5288;">Plenty of new features!</span></h4>
<p><strong>More than 300 improvements</strong> and new features have been added to the new version. You can find full details on our <a title="Changelog" href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/developers-versions/changelog/1.6.0.11" target="_blank">changelog</a>, but the major differences are as follows:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li>Improved tax and rounding management.</li>
<li>Improved specific price reductions and management of associated prices including/excluding VAT.</li>
<li>New Costa Rica localization pack.</li>
<li>Option to manage back-office orders in catalog mode.</li>
<li>Substantial upgrading of the Wishlist module.</li>
<li>Updated taxes and states for Canada.</li>
</ul>
<h4><span style="color: #2f5288;">Tax and rounding management</span></h4>
<p>This has been THE major achievement of the new version. PrestaShop now offers greatly improved management of tax and rounding by giving you a wider choice and greater freedom when setting your parameters. Here&#8217;s what you need to know:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li>Tax calculations carried out by product, product line or total products.</li>
<li>New rounding management: <em>Half_Up rounding</em> to the nearest whole number and, in particular, the <em><a title="Round half to even" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rounding#Round_half_to_even" target="_blank">Half_Even or Bankers&#8217; Rounding</a></em> method for rounding to the nearest even number.</li>
<li>Option to set the desired number of decimal places, which will affect the number of decimals used in all the price calculations for your online store.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can find details on how to make these changes to your store in our <a title="Documentation" href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/General+Preferences" target="_blank">documentation</a>!</p>
<p>So, what are you waiting for? The new year is the perfect time to update your stores!</p>
<p>&gt; <strong><a title="Download" href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download">Download PrestaShop 1.6.0.11</a></strong><br />
&gt; <strong><a title="Update" href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/Updating+PrestaShop" target="_blank">Check out our update guide</a></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/now-available-discover-and-download-prestashop-v1-6-0-11/">Now available – Discover and download PrestaShop v1.6.0.11!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/now-available-discover-and-download-prestashop-v1-6-0-11/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Develop Buyer Personas for B2C Ecommerce Marketing</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 11:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kunle Campbell (Guest Contributor)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19252</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>A buyer persona is a fictional customer who closely resembles your ideal customer. Constructing a believable, ‘human’ persona makes it much easier to understand and empathize with your customers, so building personas should be your first step –they should be ready at the planning stage of content marketing or social media campaigns. Rather than cite [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/">How to Develop Buyer Personas for B2C Ecommerce Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A buyer persona is a fictional customer who closely resembles your ideal customer. Constructing a believable, ‘human’ persona makes it much easier to understand and empathize with your customers, so building personas should be your first step –they should be ready at the planning stage of content marketing or social media campaigns.</p>
<p>Rather than cite a lot of dry statistical data, you can use that data to build a buyer persona, then internalize the customer you’re trying to attract, and relate to them as human beings.<br />
<span id="more-19252"></span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #2f5288;">How is a persona different from a definition of an ideal customer?</span></h4>
<p>Suppose you take some of the facts about your best-performing customers – they’re usually between 30 and 45, they normally reside in South London and they’re mostly men. If these facts describe your best-performing customers then they also describe the people your marketing should be optimized for. These are the people you want as Twitter followers and Facebook friends, and who you hope will have a naturally positive response to emails and other marketing – but it’s hard to picture them while creating content if all you have to go on are dry statistics.</p>
<p>Now meet Greg. Greg’s a 39-year-old man from South London who’s interested in your product. Even that basic description makes it easier to put a face to a name—and that’s all a buyer persona is: a fictional character who epitomizes your ideal customer. Now, instead of asking, “Will this perform well with x demographic?” you can ask yourself, “Will Greg like this?”</p>
<h4><span style="color: #2f5288;">How many customer personas do you need?</span></h4>
<p>Having just one customer persona is probably too limiting. Many experts recommend making between three and five customer personas, a number that’s big enough to represent the variety inherent in a fairly large audience, but small enough to retain the value of specificity.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #2f5288;">How do you go about constructing a persona?</span></h4>
<p><span style="color: #e9705d;"><strong>Begin with a business card</strong></span></p>
<p>One way to make a customer persona is to begin with a business card template and fill in the blanks for your ideal customer. You’ll want to determine:</p>
<ul style="margin: 0 0 0 30px;">
<ul>
<li>Name</li>
<li>Job title</li>
<li>Location</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p><span style="color: #e9705d;"><strong>Add a resume</strong></span></p>
<p>After that, add a resume with:</p>
<ul style="margin: 0 0 0 30px;">
<ul>
<li>Age</li>
<li>Gender</li>
<li>Family</li>
<li>Education</li>
<li>Career</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p><span style="color: #e9705d;"><strong>Hopes, fears and values</strong></span><br />
Next, try to imagine your customer’s hopes, fears and values. It’s even better if you can go beyond your imagination. A great way to gain this kind of data is to use quizzes and polls on Facebook and on your site. People love these and they consistently generate engagement – plus they give you the details necessary to create true-to-life buyer personas.</p>
<p><span style="color: #e9705d;"><strong>The elevator pitch</strong></span><br />
Finally, add an ‘elevator pitch’ – one tailored specifically to this customer. Take some time on this: you’ll probably never use it “as is,” but it will give you a clear idea of what you want to say to this customer, and that clarity will come through in other messages.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #2f5288;">Bringing personas to life</span></h4>
<p>You’ll probably find that as you develop your personas, other questions need answering to really bring them to life. Some of these might include:</p>
<p><span style="color: #e9705d;"><strong>Computer literacy.</strong></span> Are your ideal customers “digital natives,” or are they wary of new technology? How precise can you get with this? It will help immensely when you design your marketing tools.</p>
<p><span style="color: #e9705d;"><strong>Hobbies.</strong></span> What does your customer do for fun? This is an important way to humanize the personas you’re creating, but it’s also an effective means of building a more complete picture and getting both depth of background and useful detail. Again, this is information that your social contacts will often be happy to divulge via polls or other interactions.</p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #e9705d;">News sour</span><span style="color: #e9705d;">ces.</span></strong> Does Greg (remember Greg?) read <em>The Economist</em>, <em>The Guardian</em> or <em>Men’s Health</em>? Does he wait for his news sources to land on the porch or is he an RSS subscriber – or does he visit the same news websites every day?</p>
<p>This is an ‘indicator’ behavior. It tells you what news Greg cares about and how he gets it, but it also gives you broader clues about what kind of person he is, both from his preferred news sources (Fox News tends to cater to the politically conservative, while <em>Huffington Post</em> readers are usually more liberal) and formats.</p>
<p><span style="color: #e9705d;"><strong>Real quotes from actual customers</strong>,</span> drawn from interviews, polls, comments online or other sources, are a goldmine of useful information. Nothing will humanize your persona more than some actual human input.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #2f5288;">Data sources</span></h4>
<p>Where should you get the information you need to create personas?</p>
<p>Here are three good places to look:</p>
<p>Check your <span style="color: #e9705d;"><strong>site’s existing traffic analytics</strong>.</span> Site analytics will show you where your customers come from, the keywords they use to find you, how long they spend on the site once they arrive, what they look at and for how long, how much they spend and what they spend it on, and more. This set of data shows you who your audience is, what they want and how they go about getting it.</p>
<p><span style="color: #e9705d;"><strong>Research your social media.</strong></span> Use social media listening skills to build an image of your customers via their Facebook and Twitter interactions with your brand. For retail-specific insights, especially ones that relate to your customers’ likes, dislikes, tastes and ideas, Pinterest is of increasing value.</p>
<p><span style="color: #e9705d;"><strong>Ask your audience</strong> </span>questions. Your customers know themselves. They know what they want and what they like – and if you give them a chance, they’ll often be very happy to tell you. Use surveys, interviews and polls to gather data that will allow you to create effective marketing personas. A persona is a fiction, but to be useful it has to be rooted in truth. Real data will reveal that truth and the more of it that comes from from customers, the better.</p>
<p>When you’re making decisions about how to orient your marketing efforts, you should almost feel like your customer persona is in the room with you. In the same way you know if your best friend is going to like something, you should know if your customer persona will like, hate, or love everything about it. And don’t forget to name your personas!</p>
<h4>Kunle’s Bio:</h4>
<p>Kunle Campbell is a specialist eCommerce marketing consultant who works with mid-tier online retailers. He helps drive business growth and profitability through customer acquisition (driving traffic), conversion optimization and customer retention. All of his strategies are data and metric driven. You can read some more of Kunle’s articles on the company’s blog at <a href="http://www.2xmedia.co/" target="_blank">2x Media</a>. Also follow him on <a href="https://twitter.com/KunleTCampbell" target="_blank">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://plus.google.com/+KunleCampbell/" target="_blank">Google+</a> and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/kunletcampbell" target="_blank">Facebook</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/">How to Develop Buyer Personas for B2C Ecommerce Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Selling Digital Products Online: a Success Story</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-digital-products-online-a-success/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-digital-products-online-a-success/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 14:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Magali Ferber]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19210</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Dulzura de Papel is a PrestaShop store designed and developed by Jimena, a passionate graphic designer, photographer, and graphic studio owner from Buenos Aires. She found a niche market in selling customizable themed decorations for children parties such as birthdays, baby showers and baptisms. Jimena’s dreams are big and she trusts PrestaShop to support her [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-digital-products-online-a-success/">Selling Digital Products Online: a Success Story</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dulzura de Papel is a PrestaShop store designed and developed by Jimena, a passionate graphic designer, photographer, and graphic studio owner from Buenos Aires. She found a niche market in selling customizable themed decorations for children parties such as birthdays, baby showers and baptisms.<br />
<span id="more-19210"></span><br />
Jimena’s dreams are big and she trusts PrestaShop to support her as she takes on new challenges like expanding her shop beyond Argentina’s boundaries through to the rest of the world. In this article, we share Jimena’s success story and her ecommerce advice for fellow merchants looking to sell downloadable products online.</p>
<h2 style="color: #ff61b0">An entrepreneurial mom</h2>
<p>Through her daughter’s school, Jimena met fellow moms who inspired the idea behind Dulzura de Papel. “I wanted to create a beautiful, yet quick and easily customizable solution for moms who want a special party for their kids, but have no time to deal with decorations.” With Dulzura de Papel, customers can download customizable themed decorations for children parties.</p>
<p>“This is a slow change from my physical graphic studio to a web store that can run on its own”, shares Jimena, “and this migration will give me the flexibility to do what I love: spending time with my daughter.”</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-19212" title="DulzuraDePapel2" alt="An Entrepreneurial Mom" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/DulzuraDePapel2.png" width="580" height="257" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #ff61b0">The perfect software for her dream store</h2>
<p>Finding the perfect software wasn’t easy. “I first tried to build the store in WordPress because I was familiar with it. I bought modules and tried to install them, but it was extremely difficult. Even the WordPress Phone Support in Argentina told me it would be hard to make it work the way I wanted.”</p>
<p>Determined, Jimena searched for another software with features that will allow her to run a digital online store. “PrestaShop had everything I was looking for and even more.” Jimena was impressed with native features that allow her to successfully sell her digital products. “The stock version already has very powerful functionalities, such as the IP Geo-localization and the multi-language option.”</p>
<h2 style="color: #ff61b0">The online marketing strategy</h2>
<p>Having launched Dulzura de Papel, the next step was to drive traffic to her website using social media and other marketing strategies. Jimena advertises her brand and concept through her Facebook page (with over 26K fans) all at the low cost of zero. To drive traffic to the website, she shares links on social media that take customers to free products on her online store. She also promotes sales on major Argentinian shopping days including: Mother’s Day, Father’s Day, Children’s Day and Teacher’s Day.</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-19213" title="DulzuraDePapel3" alt="The Online Marketing Strategy" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/DulzuraDePapel3.png" width="580" height="291" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #ff61b0">A simple buying process</h2>
<p>Digital products require no inventory or shipping logistics, but it is essential to have a clear and simple buying process. The checkout process should also be easy because little information is needed. Jimena shortened her checkout process, with PrestaShop Addons’ One Page Checkout.</p>
<p>Through this simplified checkout process, Dulzura de Papel’s customers make their payments, receive a link via email, then download a Zip file with High Quality PDFs.</p>
<p>Because many of Dulzura de Papel’s customers are sometimes unfamiliar with downloadable products, Jimena uses various methods to guide them:</p>
<div style="margin-left: 15px;font-size: 14px"><span style="color: #ff31b0;font-weight: bold">1.</span> <span style="font-weight: bold">Information Pages and Demo Product:</span> “How to buy” and “How it works” tabs in the main menu take you to static pages that clearly explain every step of the buying process. Customers also have access to a sample PDF that demonstrates how fast and easy it is to edit the text on the designs once they make a purchase.<span style="color: #ff31b0;font-weight: bold">2.</span> <span style="font-weight: bold">Pop-Up:</span> A pop-up message is generated after each purchase, to reassure and remind customers that an email has been sent with the link to download the product.<span style="color: #ff31b0;font-weight: bold">3.</span> <span style="font-weight: bold">Guide:</span> A tutorial is attached to the email with editing and printing instruction as well as other tips and ideas.</div>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-19214" title="DulzuraDePapel4" alt="A Simple Buying Process" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/DulzuraDePapel4.png" width="580" height="282" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #ff61b0">The protection of her digital product’s copyright</h2>
<p>The same way Jimena explains the checkout process for her customers, she clarifies the terms of use. She highlights that sharing, selling or publishing any design is an infringement of Dulzura de Papel’s Copyright.</p>
<p>“PrestaShop’s software includes a digital product configuration that generates download links valid only for 30 days after the purchase, limited to up to 3 downloads. This is great because it limits the risk of diffusion.” Additionally, Jimena password protects the products in case a customer tries to open it on any design software to modify the illustrations. “Because all the products include a trademark that reads ‘dulzuradepapel.com’, I don’t want anyone to modify the design. Of course, you can’t control absolutely everything that customers do, but these are great ways of enforcing copyright rules.”</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-19215" title="DulzuraDePapel5" alt="The protection of her digital product’s copyright" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/DulzuraDePapel5.png" width="580" height="327" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #ff61b0">The future of Dulzura de Papel</h2>
<p>“Most of my customers come from Argentina, Mexico and other Spanish speaking countries,” claims Jimena, “For now my store is only available in Spanish. My plan is to translate my website into different languages, starting with English and Portuguese, so that people from anywhere in the world will be able to buy and download my designs. PrestaShop allows me to do just that.”</p>
<p>“My advice to all the merchants starting out is to take the step. PrestaShop is a safe, versatile and dynamic software with many benefits and options that can make almost anything come true.” Jimena’s dedication led her to create a beautiful and successful online store with PrestaShop &#8212; turning her dream into a reality.</p>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="20%" />
<p>Inspired to make your dreams come true? Get started with <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">PrestaShop</a>’s free and open source ecommerce software. Not ready to start selling just yet? Read more <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/category/ecommerce-success-stories/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Success Stories</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-digital-products-online-a-success/">Selling Digital Products Online: a Success Story</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-digital-products-online-a-success/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 10 Ecommerce Newsletters of 2014 from PrestaShop merchants</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-10-ecommerce-newsletters-of-2014-from-prestashop-merchants/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-10-ecommerce-newsletters-of-2014-from-prestashop-merchants/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 14:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19168</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>It seems like just yesterday we were making summer plans, but with a blink of an eye, the year has passed and we’re almost into 2015. Throughout this year, we’ve seen some great newsletters from PrestaShop merchants. Although it was hard, we’ve narrowed them down to the top 10 ecommerce newsletters of 2014. We’ve listed [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-10-ecommerce-newsletters-of-2014-from-prestashop-merchants/">Top 10 Ecommerce Newsletters of 2014 from PrestaShop merchants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It seems like just yesterday we were making summer plans, but with a blink of an eye, the year has passed and we’re almost into 2015. Throughout this year, we’ve seen some great newsletters from PrestaShop merchants.</p>
<p>Although it was hard, we’ve narrowed them down to the top 10 ecommerce newsletters of 2014. We’ve listed each newsletter’s subject line, shop, reasons why we think it’s great and what you should try next year. Let’s get started!</p>
<p><span id="more-19168"></span></p>
<div style="float: left; width: 340px; margin-right: 10px;">
<h4 style="color: #1296a3;"><span style="color: #000000;">1.</span> Thank You for Signing Up &#8211; Here is Your Voucher! by <a style="color: #1296a3; text-decoration: underline;" href="http://www.bloch.com.au/" target="_blank">Bloch Australia</a></h4>
<p><strong>Why it’s great:</strong> This email rewards customers for subscribing to newsletter and encourages them to shop with a discount code. The timeliness of this coupon code is key in driving conversions and convincing customers to make their first purchase.<br />
<strong>What to try:</strong> Welcome new customers with a coupon.</p>
<p>(<a href="http://us5.campaign-archive2.com/?u=9c73a1a1b6076ffb51472af60&amp;id=cbcc67ef03&amp;e=3598629b90" target="_blank">View it live</a>)</p>
</div>
<p><img class=" wp-image-19170 alignright" title="1. Thank You for Signing Up Here is Your Voucher" alt="Bloch Australia" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/1.-Thank-You-for-Signing-Up-Here-is-Your-Voucher.png" width="210" height="280" /></p>
<div style="float: left; width: 340px; margin-right: 10px;">
<h4 style="color: #1296a3;"><span style="color: #000000;">2.</span> International Delivery &amp; New Tools by <a style="color: #1296a3; text-decoration: underline;" href="https://www.eatingtools.com/" target="_blank">Eating Tools</a></h4>
<p><strong>Why it’s great:</strong> Newsletters give the perfect opportunity to reach out to your customers. Use it to tell them about new services like international shipping or new products. This newsletter does a great job at both and draws us in by share the new product’s story.<br />
<strong>What to try:</strong> Tell customers about new services!</p>
<p>(<a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/2-large1.png" target="_blank">Click to Enlarge</a>)</p>
</div>
<p><img class="alignright wp-image-19181" title="2. eatingtools" alt="Eating Tools" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/2.-eatingtools.png" width="210" height="280" /></p>
<div style="float: left; width: 340px; margin-right: 10px;">
<h4 style="color: #1296a3;"><span style="color: #000000;">3.</span> ARTOYZ NEWS 211 : Artoyz’s new look with news! by <a style="color: #1296a3; text-decoration: underline;" href="http://artoyz.com/" target="_blank">Artoyz</a></h4>
<p><strong>Why it’s great:</strong> This newsletter announces the new shop design so customers expect and aren’t confused by the updated design. Most merchants get so excited for their new website design, they forget to tell customers about it – don’t let it be you.<br />
<strong>What to try:</strong> Announce your website redesign.</p>
<p>(<a href="http://us3.campaign-archive1.com/?u=5fc4d904321aa12ac274e17be&amp;id=08449cf5da&amp;e=951556627b" target="_blank">View it live</a>)</p>
</div>
<p><img class="alignright  wp-image-19184" title="3. ARTOYZ NEWS 211   Artoyz fait peau neuve avec le plein de news" alt="Artoyz" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/3.-ARTOYZ-NEWS-211-Artoyz-fait-peau-neuve-avec-le-plein-de-news.png" width="210" height="280" /></p>
<div style="float: left; width: 340px; margin-right: 10px;">
<h4 style="color: #1296a3;"><span style="color: #000000;">4.</span> CITIZEN : Extra thin Eco-Drive watches by <a style="color: #1296a3; text-decoration: underline;" href="http://www.timefy.com/fr/" target="_blank">Timefy</a></h4>
<p><strong>Why it’s great:</strong> Timefy features the brand, Citizen, up and center in both the subject line and newsletter content. It’s great for building your store’s credibility and grabbing your customers’ attention. This is especially true if you sell well-known brand names.<br />
<strong>What to try:</strong> Highlight popular brands.</p>
<p>(<a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/4-Large1.png" target="_blank">Click to Enlarge</a>)</p>
</div>
<p><img class="alignright  wp-image-19185" title="4. CITIZEN les montres extra plates Eco Drive" alt="Timefy" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/4.-CITIZEN-les-montres-extra-plates-Eco-Drive-julie.liu-prestashop.com-Prestashop-SA-Mail.png" width="210" height="280" /></p>
<div style="float: left; width: 340px; margin-right: 10px;">
<h4 style="color: #1296a3;"><span style="color: #000000;">5.</span> welcome bordeaux ! by <a style="color: #1296a3; text-decoration: underline;" href="http://tinycottons.com/" target="_blank">Tiny Cottons</a></h4>
<p><strong>Why it’s great:</strong> To start, we love their super short subject line because it’s effortless to read. Once you open the email, the newsletter is dedicated entirely to one topic, or in this case, color &#8211; Bordeaux.<br />
<strong>What to try:</strong> Feature a season’s hottest color.</p>
<p>(<a href="http://us7.campaign-archive1.com/?u=ebdd970f3e0157c26ecb9f6cf&amp;id=a8d17f9b8d&amp;e=1de933fd50" target="_blank">View it live</a>)</p>
</div>
<p><img class="alignright  wp-image-19187" title="5. welcome bordeaux" alt="Tiny Cottons" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/5.-welcome-bordeaux.png" width="210" height="280" /></p>
<div style="float: left; width: 340px; margin-right: 10px;">
<h4 style="color: #1296a3;"><span style="color: #000000;">6.</span> NEW IN: NEOPRENE COLLECTION by <a style="color: #1296a3; text-decoration: underline;" href="http://www.bimbaylola.com/" target="_blank">Bimba y Lola</a></h4>
<p><strong>Why it’s great:</strong> Try adding some pizazz to your 2015 newsletters with .gif images. Bimba y Lola used them to feature multiple products at once, while keeping the email short and simple. Get started by creating your own with this free <a href="http://gifmaker.me/" target="_blank">online gif maker</a>.<br />
<strong>What to try:</strong> Bring products to life with gifs.</p>
<p>(<a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/6.-large-bimba-y-lola.gif" target="_blank">Click to Enlarge</a>)</p>
</div>
<p><img class="alignright  wp-image-19188" title="6. bimba y lola" alt="Bimba y Lola" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/6.-bimba-y-lola.gif" width="210" height="280" /></p>
<div style="float: left; width: 340px; margin-right: 10px;">
<h4 style="color: #1296a3;"><span style="color: #000000;">7.</span> Julie, enjoy exclusive access to summer + PLUS SHIP FREE by <a style="color: #1296a3; text-decoration: underline;" href="http://condura.com.au/" target="_blank">Condura</a></h4>
<p><strong>Why it’s great:</strong> The personalization in the subject line immediately grabs our attention. Adding your customers’ name can make a standard message seem personal. Then once a customer opens this newsletter, there is a coupon code enticing customers (like me) to shop.<br />
<strong>What to try:</strong> Personalize emails with customer information.</p>
<p>(<a href="http://condura.cmail2.com/t/ViewEmail/t/1E34C373FBF72796/34BA5AA3877E8DFD6A4D01E12DB8921D" target="_blank">View it live</a>)</p>
</div>
<p><img class="alignright  wp-image-19189" title="7. Redirecting" alt="Condura" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/7.-Redirecting.png" width="210" height="280" /></p>
<div style="float: left; width: 340px; margin-right: 10px;">
<h4 style="color: #1296a3;"><span style="color: #000000;">8.</span> 15% off Mokosh skincare | Filter fluoride by 97% | Hot new Veggie spiralizer | $10 off Bokashi composting kit by <a style="color: #1296a3; text-decoration: underline;" href="http://www.biome.com.au/" target="_blank">Biome</a></h4>
<p><strong>Why it’s great:</strong> The subject lines does a great job summarizing the entire newsletter. Even before I open it, I know the deals I can expect within the email. If I’m looking for something in particular, I know where it is listed.<br />
<strong>What to try:</strong> Promote your sale in the subject line</p>
<p>(<a href="https://go.madmimi.com/redirects/1412734136-300912bc6d3c77d0b3382af796aabb54-15b3b47?pa=25524177318&amp;amx=6812250723" target="_blank">View it live</a>)</p>
</div>
<p><img class="alignright  wp-image-19190" title="8. 15  off Mokosh skincare Filter fluoride by 97 Hot new Veggie spiralizer 10 off Bokashi composting kit" alt="Biome" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/8.-15-off-Mokosh-skincare-Filter-fluoride-by-97-Hot-new-Veggie-spiralizer-10-off-Bokashi-composting-kit.png" width="210" height="280" /></p>
<div style="float: left; width: 340px; margin-right: 10px;">
<h4 style="color: #1296a3;"><span style="color: #000000;">9.</span> Gifts to Put a Spring in Mom&#8217;s Step! by <a style="color: #1296a3; text-decoration: underline;" href="http://www.gretelhome.com/" target="_blank">Gretel Home</a></h4>
<p><strong>Why it’s great:</strong> Holidays roll around like clockwork. Gift ideas take the stress out of holiday shopping by making it effortlessly easy to find the perfect present. This newsletter does a great job in helping customers purchase the perfect Mother’s day gift by suggesting products for all types of moms.<br />
<strong>What to try:</strong> Feature products with gift guides.</p>
<p>(<a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/9-large1.png" target="_blank">Click to Enlarge</a>)</p>
</div>
<p><img class="alignright  wp-image-19191" title="9. Gifts To Put a Spring in Mom s Step" alt="Gretel Home" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/9.-Gifts-To-Put-a-Spring-in-Mom-s-Step.png" width="210" height="280" /></p>
<div style="float: left; width: 340px; margin-right: 10px;">
<h4 style="color: #1296a3;"><span style="color: #000000;">10.</span> It&#8217;s National Handbag Day! 20% Off Bags! by <a style="color: #1296a3; text-decoration: underline;" href="http://www.whatgoesaroundnyc.com/" target="_blank">What goes around comes around</a></h4>
<p><strong>Why it’s great:</strong> Who doesn’t love a great celebration? Although National Handbag Day isn’t widely celebrated throughout the world, it’s very relevant for this PrestaShop store. We love how they thought outside the box!<br />
<strong>What to try:</strong> Celebrate unique yet relevant holidays.</p>
<p>(<a href="http://www.whatgoesaroundnyc.com/news/2014/101014.html" target="_blank">View it live</a>)</p>
</div>
<p><img class="alignright  wp-image-19192" title="10. It s National Handbag Day" alt="What goes around comes around" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/12/10.-It-s-National-Handbag-Day.png" width="210" height="280" /></p>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="20%" />
<p>Which of these newsletters will inspire yours in 2015? Tell us in the comments below. Ready to start sending your own newsletters? Purchase the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/4932-newsletter-statistics.html" target="_blank">Newsletter Module from PrestaShop Addons</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-10-ecommerce-newsletters-of-2014-from-prestashop-merchants/">Top 10 Ecommerce Newsletters of 2014 from PrestaShop merchants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-10-ecommerce-newsletters-of-2014-from-prestashop-merchants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
